(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-27T17:06:19.663021",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
痛くて目を塞いでも 聞こえてしまう不安ショー
Even with my eyes shut tight in pain, the anxiety show keeps playing.
悩んでも変わらないから なんかんだやるしかないか
Fretting changes nothing, so I guess I've got to do it anyway.
壊れるならいっそ 直しやすいように
If it's going to break, I'd rather it be easy to fix.
どんな形 目指せるかな
What kind of shape can I aim for?
助走なしのジャンプ 紐なしでダイブ
A jump with no run-up, a dive with no cord.
今日のあたし褒めてあげたいじゃんか
I want to praise myself for today, don't I?
息死にたい もっと響きたい
I want to catch my breath, I want to echo further.
ねえ あたし以上が見れるかも 妄想止まんない いや
Hey, maybe I'll see something beyond myself—my delusions won't stop, no.
ファッションビート 嗅ぎでみちゃう？
Shall we catch a whiff of the fashion beat?
夢にあうそなんて吐きやしないな
I won't spit out lies about meeting in dreams.
叶えるのはあたし自身か それとも誰かにお任せか
Will I make it happen myself, or leave it to someone else?
ただただ自分に勝ちたい
I just, simply want to win against myself.
ニューファッションビート 愛を嗜もう
A new fashion beat—let's savor love.
負けるなんてごめんだ 味がないな
Losing is out of the question; it has no flavor.
何度でも灰になる進化 生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Evolution to turn to ashes over and over, the personification of a reborn bug.
まだまだ腐らせてあげないそう、ない
I won't let it rot just yet, no, never.
チクチク刺してくるのは飽き飽きしてるわ
I'm sick and tired of those prickly stings.
ごめん愚痴雑な言葉遊びはどうかしんと仕舞っておいて
Sorry, put away petty complaints and crude wordplay nicely.
あたしこそがライバル 当たり前の解釈
I am my own rival—that's a given interpretation.
どうしたらいい分かっているのに
Even though I know what I should do,
助走なしのジャンプ 紐なしでダイブ
A jump with no run-up, a dive with no cord.
今日のあたし出来る気しないなって
Feeling like I can't do it today—
気にしないなんて無理じゃない？
Isn't it impossible not to care?
ねえあたし意外と比べてもクソつまなんないじゃんか
Hey, compared to anything else, I'm damn boring anyway.
あうぜー
Oh man...
ファッションビート 嗅ぎでみちゃう？
Shall we catch a whiff of the fashion beat?
夢にあうそなんて吐きやしないな
I won't spit out lies about meeting in dreams.
叶えるのはあたし自身かそれとも誰かにお任せか
Will I make it happen myself, or leave it to someone else?
ただただ自分に勝ちたい
I just, simply want to win against myself.
ニューファッションビート 愛を嗜もう
A new fashion beat—let's savor love.
Nya! Hello!!
The beautiful days!!
刮目しちゃってくれ！
Open your eyes wide and check it out!
Please call 『Elite』!!
Please call "Elite"!!
Funky dancin' baby! ah
さあ、待ったなしだ！始めちゃえ！
Now, no waiting! Let's get started!
今日も気合引き締めてえやで挑戦だ
Pulling it together today too, it's a challenge!
躊躇は厳禁足踏みしないで
Hesitation is strictly forbidden, don't stall!
一緒に「せーの！」でもっと前に行こうねぇ？
Together on "Ready!", let's go further ahead, okay?
さあ、なんとかなっちゃえ！飛び込んで！
Now, somehow it'll work out! Dive right in!
なんたってじっとしても人生は冒険だ
No matter what, even staying still, life is an adventure!
こんがらがったらまたわかんないぞ
If it gets tangled up, you won't understand it anymore!
道のりは困難だ！なんだんだ！上等だ！
The path is difficult! What is this! Bring it on!
メソメソしちゃって気持ちに「待った」しちゃって
Sniffling and putting a "hold" on your feelings,
あれ一体全体どうしたん？絶対絶命！？
What on earth happened? Desperate situation?!
君たちには涙は似合わないね！
Tears don't suit you guys at all!
大大大冒険に飛び出そうぜ！良いじゃんねぇ！
Let's dash out into a huge adventure! Isn't that great?!
大大大失敗も重ねて成長して
Accumulating huge failures and growing,
happyなfeel soで君と笑い話にしよう
With a happy "feel so", let's laugh about it with you!
大大大問題も吹き飛ばせ！いつか大大大団円の素敵な結末へ
Blow away huge problems too! Toward a grand finale someday!
please me! さあ付いてきて？
Please me! Now, will you come along?
進め！前代未聞のnew world!
Advance! An unprecedented new world!
Let's go!
あな間違いってるまっとポケットも掘ってる
You're making mistakes, digging deep pockets too!
勉強勉強！はいはいはい知ってます待ってなんか違ってる！
Study, study! Yeah, I know! Wait, something's wrong!
ぶっちゃけ有識者の皆様に感謝してます！nice comment待ってんぜあね
Frankly, thanks to all experts! Waiting for nice comments, yeah.
ウジウジしちゃって心にロックしちゃって
Hesitating and locking it in your heart,
ほらだんだんだんだんダウンしちゃって絶体絶命！？
Look, getting depressed step by step... Desperate situation?!
君たちには笑顔が足りてないね！
You guys don't have enough smiles!
大大大好きじゃ済まされない！良いじゃんねぇ！
"Super love" isn't enough! Isn't that great?!
大大大満足のその上の感動を！
Give me emotion even greater than super satisfaction!
もっと欲しがっちゃって！豪快に贅沢に行こう
Wanting even more! Let's go grand and luxuriously!
全然前進しないなって凹んじゃったって
Even if you get depressed thinking you're making no progress,
ならば全身全霊エンジン全開！本気の全力で
Then use your body and soul with engines wide open!
Nya! Hello!!
さあ美しいに
Now, to be beautiful,
意気込んで進め！freedom way!
Charge ahead and advance! Freedom way!
乗り遅れんなよ皆！
Don't miss out, everyone!
声を聞かせてくれ！Yeah!
Let me hear your voice! Yeah!
歌おう声高らかに
Let's sing out loud and clear
ベイビーベイビーなんていうかあぁなんだかちょっと言い表せない
Baby baby, how should I put it, ah, I can't quite express it
一人ぼっちで見てた光景を今はきっとあなたと冒険してる！
The scenery I saw alone, now I'm surely adventuring with you!
大大大好きじゃ収まらない！
"Super love" can't contain it!
だから最大最高レベルにガチの全力で！
Therefore, at the maximum highest level with serious effort!
Nya! Hello!! 届けちゃうぜ！
Nya! Hello!! I'll deliver it to you!
ずっと大冒険しよう Yeah!!
Let's keep having a grand adventure, Yeah!!
大大大問題も吹き飛ばせ！
Blow away huge problems too!
いつか大大大団円の素敵な結末へ
Toward a wonderful grand finale someday!
please me! さあ付いてきて？
Please me! Now, will you come along?
進め！前代未聞のnew world!
Advance! An unprecedented new world!
刮目しちゃってくれ！
Open your eyes wide and check it out!
Please call 『Elite』!!
Please call "Elite"!!
Funky dancin' baby! ah
とくべチュ、して？
Won't you give me a special kiss?
Oh baby! I love you! じゃ足りない！
"Oh baby! I love you!" is not enough!
一番大事がいい 君が作るオリジナルの
The most important thing is best, your very own original
特別チューして！
Special kiss!
まぶしくって目が覚めて
Blindingly, opening my eyes,
愛しく思ってよ
think of me so fondly.
眠り姫のように
Like a sleeping princess,
優しく口付けて
gently kiss me.
ゴミめいたこの世界
In this trash-like world,
ピュアがかる君がいる
you, so pure, are here.
全てに触れずに
Without touching anything,
2人だけでいよう
let's be just the two of us.
私のこと独占して
Monopolize me completely,
君だけのモノになってもいい
I don't mind being only yours.
なんでもない日の「なんでもない」気付いてね
Notice the "it's nothing" on ordinary days.
Oh baby I love you じゃ足りない
"Oh baby, I love you" isn't enough,
君の「特別」にして
make me your "special one."
ねぇもっと君にキス
Hey, give me more kisses,
もう私は君でいっぱいよ
I'm already filled completely with you.
ほどけないリボン結び
An untieable ribbon knot,
小指キュッて縛って
tie our pinkies tightly together.
そうよ一生一緒がいいもん
That's right, I want to be together forever.
とくべチュが欲しい
I want a special kiss.
2人きり週末は
On just our weekend together,
奏でてよ ハーモニー
play our harmony.
流れ星見たら
If I see a shooting star,
私を想ってほしい
I want you to think of me.
あまぁい君なのに
Even though you're so sweet,
広い街吸い込まれ
swallowed up by the wide city,
戦う姿に
in your fighting posture,
大きいほめまるだね
you deserve a big praise mark.
好きなとこ、優しいとこ
Your good points, your kind points,
嫌いなとこも優しいとこ
even your disliked points are kind.
誰にもあげない
I won't give you to anyone.
私だけ独り占め！
I'll monopolize you all to myself!
うだって今までの人と同じはいらないんです
That's why I don't need anyone like before.
ねぇもっと君も私のため生きてほしいんです
Hey, I want you to live more for my sake too.
だからウサギと私たちは寂しくさせないで
So don't make the bunny and me lonely.
そんなんじゃ束縛じゃないわ
That's not even binding,
苦しいのが好き
I like it when it hurts.
ショートケーキイチゴみたいに包ってはいい？
Can I be wrapped up like a strawberry on a cake?
赤く甘い恋だもん
Because love is red and sweet.
誰かにあげた「大好き」も返してもらって全部私にちょーだい、もっと！
Take back the 'I love you' given to others and give it all to me!
君は神様が作る
You are created by God,
奇跡のようなヒト
a miraculous person.
拗ねた顔もその寝顔も守ってあげるね
I'll protect your sulking and sleeping face.
Oh baby I love you じゃ足りない
"Oh baby, I love you" isn't enough,
君の「特別」にして
make me your "special one."
ねぇもっと君にキス
Hey, give me more kisses,
もう私は君でいっぱいよ
I'm already filled completely with you.
ほどけないリボン結び
An untieable ribbon knot,
小指キュッて縛って
tie our pinkies tightly together.
ねぇbaby最初で最後のとくべチュにしてね
Hey baby, make this our first and last special kiss.
はい、みんな、にゃっはろー！
Hi everyone, Nya-hello!
エリート巫女アイドルのおさくらみこです！
It's elite miko idol Sakura Miko!
さくらみこ生誕祭2026 ファッションビート肉ってくれて、どうもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Sakura Miko's Birthday Festival 2026 'Fashion Beat'!
イェーイ！
Yay!
え、今年でなんとみこちゃん18.8歳になりました！
And this year, somehow, Miko-chan became 18.8 years old!
はい、あの0.1でね、刻んでいく系のVTuberですから。
Yes, because I'm a VTuber who increments by 0.1.
今年も18.8歳になっちゃいます、わぁい！
This year I'll become 18.8 years old again, yay!
え、そしてそして、今回のライブのテーマは「ファッションビート」にちなんでですね、「ファッション」となっております。
And, the theme of this live is 'Fashion Beat', so the theme is 'fashion'.
いろんなね、演出がもりだくさんなので、ぜひ楽しんでください。
There are lots of various productions, so please enjoy them.
じゃあね、ちょっとまあファッションちなんでみこちゃんもちょっと衣装チェンジしよっかなー。
Well, in line with fashion, maybe Miko-chan will do a little costume change.
はい、上無いててください。
Yes, please look up.
ちゃーんと！
Ta-da!
ということが、クリスマスのね、ライブではね、あの...
So, at the Christmas live, uh...
しなかったこちらのキャストオフバージョンになっております。
This is the cast-off version that wasn't...
こんな感じになってます かわいいでしょ ちょっとセクシーですけどね はい
How is it? Isn't it cute? A bit sexy, though! Yeah!
はーい
Yeah!
次の曲はこれで披露しようと思っております。そして、え、先ほどね2曲ねお送りしましたがどうでしたか？
We'll be performing the next song with this look. And how did you like the two songs we performed earlier?
みこのオリジナル曲の「ダイダイダイファンタジスタ」と、
Miko's original song "Dai Dai Dai Fantasista,"
そして、みこのね、あの、大好きなアイドルさんのいくらむさんの特別チュートリアルは、視聴していただきました！
and did you enjoy the special tutorial by Miko's beloved idol, Ikuram-san?
とっても可愛かったでしょ？ きゅるるん、きゅるるん！
It was super cute, right? Kyururun, kyururun!
あ、そうだ！
Oh, that's right!
ステージもねちょっと見せたいんですけど、
I'd also like to show you the stage, so
見てくんなさい。
please take a look.
こちら、今回のテーマにちなんで作っていただきました！ドレッサーとかね、めちゃくちゃね、なんかこう、みこがこ、こびとになったみたいな感じですけどね、
This was made for us based on this time's theme! With the dresser and all, it feels like Miko became a little person,
ね、とっても可愛くなっております。
and it's turned out super cute.
そしてこちらのトルソーね、みこちゃんの歴代の衣装とかも少し飾っております。全部じゃないんですけどね。はい。
And here on the torso, we're also displaying some of Miko-chan's past outfits. Not all of them, though. Yeah.
え、そして、え、最後にですね、たくさんの告知があったりとか、新曲のお披露目もございますので、ぜひ楽しんでもらえたらなと思っております！
And lastly, we have plenty of announcements and the unveiling of a new song, so I hope you'll enjoy them!
では！ 早速ゲストパート行こうと思いますよ。おしこをして
Now then! We'll be heading right into the guest part.
それではこの後も楽しんでね！
Well then, keep enjoying the rest of the show!
ファッション モンスター
Fashion Monster
おもしろいって 言いたいのに
Don't you think it's boring
言えないなんて つまらないでしょ
when you wanna say it's interesting, but you can't?
おなじになって いい子でなんて
I don't wanna be the same and be a good girl,
いたくなくって キミもそうでしょう
I'm sure you don't either
誰かの ルールに しばられたくないの
I don't want to be bound by someone else's rules
わがまま ドキドキ このままでいたい
I'm so selfish, my heart is pounding, I want to stay the way I am
ファッション モンスター
Fashion Monster
このせまいこころの檻もこわして自由になりたいの
I want to break the narrow cage of my heart and be free
ファッション モンスター
Fashion Monster
感覚をとぎすませて キミのように
I can sharpen up my senses, like you
すいこまれてく 螺旋模様みたいに
sucking it all in so it looks like a spiral,
i wanna be free
ファッション モンスター
Fashion Monster
ただふつうに 生きたいのに
I just want to live my life normally:
変なことって つまらないでしょ
isn't it boring to say that I'm weird?
きめつけないで いい子でなんて
Don't judge me, I don't wanna be a good girl,
いたくないって キミもそうでしょう
I'm sure you don't either
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
おもしろいって いい たい の に
Don't you think it's boring when you want to say
えない なんて つまらない でしょ
something is interesting, but you can't?
おなじ に なっ て いい 子 で なんて
I don't want to be the same and be a good girl,
いたく ない って キミ も そうでしょ
and I'm sure you don't either.
だれ か の ルール に しばら れ たく ない のに
I don't want to be bound by someone else's rules.
わがまま ドキドキ この まま で い たい
I'm so selfish, my heart's pounding, I want to stay this way.
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
この せまい こころ の なかも
I want to break the narrow cage of my heart
こわして じゆうになりたいの
and be free!
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
感覚 を とぎすませ て キミ の よう に
I can sharpen up my senses, just like you,
すいこま れ て く 螺旋 模様 みたい に I wanna be free
sucking it in like a spiral pattern—I wanna be free!
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
ただ ふつう に いき たい の に
I just want to live my life normally—
へん な こと って つまらない でしょ
isn't it boring to say that I'm weird?
きめつけ ない で いい 子 で なんて
Don't judge me, I don't wanna be a good girl,
いたく ない って キミ も そうでしょ
and I'm sure you don't either.
だれ か の ルール に しばら れ たく ない のに
I don't want to be bound by someone else's rules.
わがまま ドキドキ この まま で い たい
I'm so selfish, my heart's pounding, I want to stay this way.
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
てつの くびかさり を はずして ただ じゆう に いき たい だけ
I just want to take off this iron necklace and live freely.
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
咲き誇れ 花よ 舞い踊れ
Blooming flowers, dance and flutter wildly,
明日を 虹色に 染め上げて
dyeing tomorrow in rainbow colors!
ソイヤ！ ソイヤ！
Hey! Hey!
はじまるよー！
Here we go!
今から歌うは ウルトラ スーパー
What I'm about to sing now is an ultra-super-happy,
ハッピー とっておきのおかしの 夢色リズミカル
dreamy, rhythmical, and special treat of a song!
おかしなうえねで こころひかれて
Swept away by such a whimsical mood,
さあ、そんなお話しは とってもいいよ
well, even a story like that is just fine!
大事なのは 楽しむこころ
The most important thing is a heart that knows how to enjoy itself.
準備はいいな 遅れないでね
Get ready, don't be late, okay?
3, 2, 1 で 飛び出せ
In 3, 2, 1, jump right out!
ワクワクしたいの？ ドキドキしたくない？
Wanna be thrilled? Don't you want your heart to race?
ウキウキさせてよ！ もういいかい？ まあだだよ！
Let's get excited! Are you ready yet? Not yet!
なんていうか 止まらない！
How should I put it? It just won't stop!
まだまだ 明日の景色を見たいんだもん！
I still want to see tomorrow's scenery!
咲き誇れ 花よ 舞い踊れ
Blooming flowers, dance and flutter wildly,
ここが最高のフェスティバル
this is the ultimate festival!
夢中リズムでノリノリ
Riding along on the dreamy rhythm,
笑顔満開 ＝ 無限大 It's Alright!
smiles in full bloom to infinity—It's Alright!
舞い踊れ 飛び跳ねて
Dance and leap around,
君の教えて キミが聞いちゃうから
tell me everything, I'm so curious!
そんな感じで よいさ、よいさ
Feeling like that, yoisa, yoisa,
夢のビート聴かせても
let me hear the beat of our dreams!
ソイヤ！ ソイヤ！
Hey! Hey!
はじまるよー！
Here we go!
続けて歌うは ウルトラ スーパー
Continuing to sing is an ultra-super-happy,
ハッピー とっておきのおかしの 夢色リズミカル
dreamy, rhythmical, and special treat of a song!
もしかしましても 先もいたっけ？
Could it be that we were here before too?
まあそんなお話しは とってもいいよ
Well, even a story like that is just fine!
大事なのは 信じるこころ
The most important thing is a heart that believes.
キミだけ聴こえる リズムに任せて
Leave it to the rhythm that only you can hear.
星空きらめく街を もっともっと照らして
Shine even brighter on the twinkling starlit streets!
飛び出せ 飛び出せ
Jump right out!
ワクワクしたいの？ ドキドキしたくない？
Wanna be thrilled? Don't you want your heart to race?
ウキウキさせてよ！ もういいかい？ まあだだよ！
Let's get excited! Are you ready yet? Not yet!
なんていうか 止まらない！
How should I put it? It just won't stop!
今日も君色を輝かせて
Let's make today shine with your colors too!
咲き誇れ 花よ 舞い踊れ
Blooming flowers, dance and flutter wildly,
ここが最高のフェスティバル
this is the ultimate festival!
夢中リズムでノリノリ
Riding along on the dreamy rhythm,
笑顔満開 ＝ 無限大 It's Alright!
smiles in full bloom to infinity—It's Alright!
舞い踊れ 飛び跳ねて
Dance and leap around,
君の教えて 君の推しはだあれ？
dyeing tomorrow in your colors, who is your favorite?
辺りは同じ色 違う色は指をさされてた
Surrounded by the same colors, different colors were pointed at
怖くて隠してた 同じ色になりかけていた
I was scared and hid, almost turning into the same color
好きから逃げないで 胸を張って輝け 世界は広いよ見ごらんよ
Don't run away from what you love, hold your chest high and shine, the world is vast, go and see
わがまま育てて 媚びず夢を貫け ネガティブ自分置いていこう
Nurture our selfishness, pierce through our dreams without pandering, let's leave our negative selves behind
君の色が綺麗だった一つで 世界を彩っている花みたいで
With just your color being so beautiful, it's like a flower coloring the world
ほら照れないでいいんだよ顔上げて 特別な君でいて
Hey, don't be shy, lift your face up, be your special self
やりたい事やらなきゃ損じゃん？ 選手宣誓 他人の夢それじゃダメ！君を楽しめ
Isn't it a loss if you don't do what you want? Athlete's oath! Someone else's dream won't do! Enjoy yourself
見た目も違うのに 同じレール歩かなくちゃダメなの？
Even though our appearances are different, do we have to walk the same rail?
“恥ずかしい”夢だって 胸の奥に追いやっていいた
An "embarrassing" dream was chased deep into my chest
好きは錆びつき付いて 忘れ去られ無くなっくなる そんなの嘘だよずっといるよ
Love gets rusty and forgotten, that's a lie, I'll be here forever
ワクワクになれる 夢が胸支配して 時間さえ忘れ笑っている
Able to get excited, dreams rule my chest, laughing while forgetting even time
君の色は名前なんてなくて見とれてる 世界輝かせてる星みたいで
Your color has no name, I'm captivated, like a star making the world shine
合わせなくていいんだよそのままで 特別な君でいて
You don't have to match, just stay as you are, be your special self
ぶつかったところから 熟れていく果実のように
Like fruit ripening from where it was bumped,
僕らは些細なことで へこたれたような
We were dejected over such trivial things,
かさぶたになれずに 見切り発車で心臓を
Unable to become a scab, starting off hastily, making our hearts
息せき切って がむしゃらに
Gasping for breath, recklessly
輝く一等星を目指して 手を伸ばしたよな
Aiming for the shining first-magnitude star, we reached out our hands.
繊細されど大胆だ
Delicate yet bold,
うるさいこれが切り札だ
Noisy, this is my trump card.
泣き虫されど熱血だ
Crybaby yet passionate,
うるさいこれが持ち味だ
Noisy, this is my strong point.
未開拓 冒険地帯 好奇心 旺盛時代
Unexplored adventure zone, an era full of curiosity.
何が綺麗かは分かる 見る目ならばある
We know what is beautiful, if we have the eyes to see it.
恥ずかしいか青春は 馬鹿らしいか真剣は 僕ら全力でやってんだ
Is youth embarrassing? Is earnestness foolish? We're doing it with all our might!
振りかざせ存在を 掻き乱せ心臓を あとどれくらい続いていくだろう
Brandish our existence, stir up our hearts, I wonder how much longer it will continue.
守り抜いた青春が 何よりもの贅沢だ
The youth we protected is a luxury above all else.
きっといつか焦がれ思い返す
Surely someday we'll look back on it with yearning.
名前のない関係を 捨てきれない感情を
A nameless relationship, emotions we can't throw away,
悩んでた種の数が 昨日とはまるで違うとか
The number of seeds we worried about is completely different from yesterday,
そんなのは日常生活茶飯事で 心は素直のようだ
Such things are an everyday occurrence, and our hearts seem honest.
戦友だとか親友は うるさいどれも正解だ 初恋だとか失恋は うるさいどれも宝だ
Comrades or best friends, noisy, any of them are correct. First love or heartbreak, noisy, any of them are treasures.
人生で一日しかない今日を愛そう
Let's cherish today, the only day we have in life,
昨日はリセット
yesterday is reset,
僕達は春を青く青く塗り替える
we paint spring in vibrant blue over and over.
君はなにしてんのかな 話がしたい
What are you up to? I want to talk to you.
風に乗って青春が
Riding the wind, youth
この想いを運んで 蒼く広がる
carries these feelings as they spread out in blue.
僕ら全力を越えたいんだ
We want to surpass our utmost limits!
立ちすくむ同士だって
Even if we're standing still in hesitation,
引き連れていこうぜ
let's lead each other forward!
この上ない今日は すごいステージだよ
Today, which couldn't be better, is an amazing stage!
今しかできない事がある
There are things we can only do now,
今しかできない恋がある
there is love we can only experience now.
今しかできないから
Because we can only do it now,
僕らに隠された時間が惜しい
we cherish every fleeting moment we have.
今しか見られない 君の笑顔も 君の涙も
Even your smile and your tears that can only be seen now,
君の全ても 大人びていく
and your very everything, are growing up into adulthood.
有限だから最高だ
Because it's finite, it's the best!
恥ずかしいか青春は
Is youth embarrassing?
馬鹿らしいか真剣は
Is earnestness foolish?
僕ら全力でやってんだ
We're giving it our absolute all!
振りかざせ存在を
Brandish your existence,
かき乱せ心臓を
shake up your heartbeat!
胸に刻めば 続いていくだろう
Engrave it in your heart, and it will keep going.
守り抜いた青春が 何よりも贅沢だ
The youth we protected is more luxurious than anything else.
きっといつか 焦がれ 思い返す
Surely, one day, we'll yearn for it and look back.
名前もない関係を 捨てきれない感情を
A nameless relationship, feelings we can't completely throw away,
何気ない今日も 忘れないでね
don't forget these casual days either.
この上ない今日を 忘れないでね
Don't forget this incomparable today!
アイドルだから 挑み続けるんだ 君と夢見るんだ
Because I'm an idol, I'll keep challenging myself, dreaming with you.
不器用で悪いか 咲き誇るよ
Is it bad to be clumsy? I'll bloom proudly!
初のイベント 需要無しデフォ そんな私が夢を見た
My first event, default zero demand... That's the kind of me who dreamed.
アイドルという生き方 憧れて
Aspiring to live as an idol.
「無敵エリート」 「笑顔はチート」
"Invincible Elite," "Smiles are a Cheat,"
こんな私を見てくれる君
the you who looks at a me like this.
好きなとこはどこですか？
What do you like about me?
わがままを許して
Forgive my selfishness!
ステージ経験値 涙滲んで
Stage experience, tears welling up,
それでも絶対負けたくない
even so, I never want to lose.
花にメッセージ乗せて届け 愛で溢れますように
Delivering a message on flowers, hoping it overflows with love.
アイドルだから 挑み続けるんだ 君と夢見るんだ
Because I'm an idol, I'll keep challenging myself, dreaming with you.
不器用で悪いか 妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
Is it bad to be clumsy? I won't let it end as just a delusion.
私らしく 桜色ね
True to myself, in cherry blossom pink.
磨いたスキル 実力発揮 楽しめる日も増えてきたんだ
Polished skills, showing my true strength, days I can enjoy myself have increased.
アイドルとして生きてる 君のおかげ
Living as an idol, all thanks to you.
アホ毛はキュート 勝ち確ルート
Ahoge is cute, guaranteed winning route!
そんな私についてきてよね
Come follow a me like this!
ドジなとこも許されて
Even my clumsy side is forgiven,
最強じゃん！
I'm the strongest!
痛いの痛いのグッと飲み込んで
Swallowing down the pain and hurt,
笑顔で笑顔増やしたいな
I want to increase smiles with a smile.
桜前線が君の町に 春を届けるように
Like the cherry blossom front delivering spring to your town,
アイドルだけは譲りたくないんだ 君に見せたいんだ
I refuse to give up being an idol; I want to show it to you.
理想へ挑むよ 駆け抜けろ
Challenging my ideals, running ahead,
最高景色見せてあげる 信じていいよ 桜を
I'll show you the best view. You can believe in Sakura.
さぁ 皆で咲かせそう
Now, let's make it bloom together!
満開のピンクで世界染めて あぁ この涙はね
Dyeing the world in full-bloom pink... Ah, these tears are...
あぁこの涙はね
Ah, these tears...
悲しい方じゃないから
aren't because I'm sad,
安心して
so don't worry.
きれいだね
They're so pretty, right?
今年も誕生日をお祝いしてくれてありがとう
Thank you for celebrating my birthday this year too!
みんな大好きだよ
I love you all so much!
アイ・ラブ・ユー
I love you,
アイドルだから
because I'm an idol.
挑み続けるんだ 君と夢見るんだ
I'll keep challenging myself, dreaming with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it bad to be clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom proudly!
想いだけじゃ終わらない
It doesn't end with just feelings.
私らしく
Living true to myself,
桜色ね
in cherry blossom pink, right?
みんなありがとう！
Thank you everyone!
ありがとうね
Thank you so much.
ピース
Peace!
ありがとう
Thank you.
お祝いしてくれてありがとうね
Thank you for celebrating with me.
楽しんでる？
Are you having fun?
ありがとう
Thank you.
ありがとう、うま
Thank you, mwah!
見てるよ みんな見てるよ
I'm watching you, I'm watching everyone!
よしっ ということで ライブまだまだ盛り上がる準備できてますかー！
Alright, so are you guys ready for the live to get even more hyped?!
みんな まだまだみんな備えてねー！
Everyone, get ready for even more!
よしっ 次の曲いきまーす！
Alright, let's go to the next song!
Now I'm ready, I'm ready to go
花が咲く時が来たんだ
The time has come for flowers to bloom.
Are you ready? わかるでしょ
Are you ready? You know it.
やってみせる Make it through
I'll show you I can make it through.
ほら そんなソワソワしてたって
Hey, if you're feeling so fidgety like that,
時は過ぎ付いちゃうから 今すぐにさ
time's gonna fly by, so right now
Let's work it out
もう 目を背けやしないんだ
I won't turn my back anymore.
自分で Make it better 作る正解を
Make it better by myself, create the right answer.
I just wanna, just wanna find somebody
私よりも強気なダレカ uh
Someone stronger than me, uh.
夢中になる Make you hot
Get obsessed, make you hot.
準備体操 お済みですか？掴んだ Victory
Are you done with your warm-up exercises? Grab the victory.
So now, let's start the war!
I'm fighting my way
夢の未来 Ay-ay 信じて進むだけ
Dream future, ay-ay, just believing and moving forward.
誰にも絶対 負ける気になんかない
No way in hell I feel like losing to anyone.
君に見せたいの 彼方の景色を
I want to show you the scenery beyond.
恋に踊れ 情熱全て
Dance to love, all my passion.
もっと先を知りたい もう止まらない Ay-ay
I want to know what's further ahead, can't stop anymore, ay-ay.
I will lead the way, just come along my way
Hey! Don't kill my vibe
行こう 一番上まで
Let's go all the way to the top.
ちょっと待ってよ なんか 誤解なら困っちゃうな
Wait a minute, if there's any misunderstanding, I'd be in trouble.
ねぇ 脚落とすため 戦う訳ではないの
Hey, I'm not fighting to kick others down.
Just wanna keep challenging myself
こんな Fantasy ハマったら もっともっと欲しくなっちゃうよ
Once you get hooked on this fantasy, you'll want more and more.
もう 何も恐れはしないんだ
I won't fear anything anymore.
君となら行ける気がするから Come join us
Because I feel like I can go anywhere with you, come join us.
ほら 今聞こえて来るから
Look, it's starting to be heard now.
Yea 私の名を呼ぶ方へ
Yeah, towards the place that calls my name.
I'm fighting my way
夢の未来 Ay-ay 信じて進むだけ
Dream future, ay-ay, just believing and moving forward.
誰にも絶対 負ける気になんかない
No way in hell I feel like losing to anyone.
君に見せたいの 彼方の景色を
I want to show you the scenery beyond.
雨を受け 夜を抜け 青空の光求めた
Facing the rain, escaping the night, I sought the light of the blue sky.
Whoa 一つの無駄はないさ
Whoa, nothing is wasted.
力に変えて 輝いてくから
Turning it into power so I can shine.
Kira-kira 弾けた あぁ 神の思し召しだ
Kira-kira, droplets splattered, ah, it's the will of the gods.
連れてくよ Make you high 後悔はさせませんわ
Taking you high, I won't let you regret it.
超えるんだ Boundary So now, let's start the war!
Cross the boundary, so now, let's start the war!
I'm fighting with myself
負けなんてない Ay-ay 勝負受けて立つだけ
No losing, ay-ay, just accepting and facing the challenge.
もう自分以外 私に勝てない
No one can defeat me except myself.
君がいれば 何度も立ち上がるわ！
If you are here, I'll stand up as many times as it takes!
愛を歌え 想い全て
Sing of love, all my feelings.
逃げたくない 待てない まだ終われない
I don't want to run, I can't wait, it's not over yet.
うなるぜ
Roar,
血泥ついたって守りたい
I want to protect you, even stained in blood and mud.
革命道中だって
Even on this revolutionary journey,
君に夢中
I'm crazy about you.
暗闇染み込む世界で
In this world steeped in darkness,
見つけた
I found you.
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love.
甘くぬかるんだ眼差し
A sweetly muddy gaze,
変に色気あるから困った
So alluring it's troublesome.
手を繋ぐ勇気出したがって
Wanting to find the courage to hold hands,
身の程わきまえてちゃできないね
I can't do that if I know my place.
暗いトンネルの壁 したがたり落ちる秘密
The walls of a dark tunnel, dripping secrets.
しめやかに行こう
Let's go quietly.
ダメダメ
No way, no way,
待て待て
Wait, wait,
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace both curse and sickness.
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Would it be alright to go wild here?
ああうなるぜ
Ah, roar,
血泥ついたって守りたい
I want to protect you, even stained in blood!
革命道中だって
Even on this revolutionary journey,
君に夢中
I'm crazy about you.
暗闇染み込む世界で見つけた
In this world steeped in darkness, I found you.
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love.
なりふり構わず側にいたい
I want to stay by your side without caring.
不器用な君にも期待しちゃうよ
Expecting something from clumsy you.
しがみつけば消えそうな火に
Clinging to a fire about to go out,
恋の爪立てて近づいてもいい？
Is it okay to draw close with the claws of love?
身を任せ抱かれて全て失ってもいい
Surrendering my body, even if I lose everything.
しめやかに高鳴る心
My heart beats high and quietly.
ダメダメ 待て待て
No way, no way, wait, wait.
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace both curse and sickness.
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Would it be alright to go wild here?
泣けるぜ絶句しちゃうまで離れない
I won't leave until I'm speechless.
革命道中だって
Even on this revolutionary journey,
君に夢中
I'm crazy about you.
揺蕩う旅の狭間で 見つけた
Found in the gaps of a wandering journey.
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love.
突き進むなら二人で
If we push forward, let's do it together.
革命道中だって夢に熱中
Lost in dreams on this revolutionary journey.
ダメダメ 待て待て
No way, no way, wait, wait.
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace both curse and sickness.
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいよね
It's fine to go wild here, right?
怖くたってうなるぜ血泥ついたって守りたい
Even if scared, I'll roar and protect you.
革命道中だって君に夢中
Even on this revolutionary journey, I'm crazy about you.
暗闇染み込む世界で見つけた
In this world steeped in darkness, I found you.
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love.
飛べ、起こせ！願うは事故
Fly, awaken! Wishing for an accident.
一世一代さ何賭ける？自問自答
Once in a lifetime, what will you bet?
勝つか負けるかドローなんてないわ
There's no draw between winning and losing.
幕開けるわ
The curtain rises.
抱き占めたいから 2本足で歩く
I want to hold you close, so I walk on two legs.
一人じゃ寂しいから君と息すうよ
I'm lonely on my own, so I'll breathe with you.
「ねえママ、僕好きな人が出来たんだ。」
"Hey Mom, I found someone I like."
“おめでとう”
"Congratulations."
会いたいよ
I want to see you.
ねえ君は今頃誰の乳を吸って生きているの？
Hey, whose milk are you sucking to live right now?
言葉はもう覚えたかな？
Have you learned words yet?
“よくできました。今すぐ行くね。”
"Well done. I'm coming right now."
あれ？おかしいな…
Huh? That's strange...
君を抱き占めるために浮かべた前足が 何故か君を傷付け始めるんだ
The forelegs I floated to embrace you... are somehow starting to hurt you.
覚え立ての言葉だって 君に突き刺すナイフ 切り裂く人生
Even my newly learned words are a knife piercing you, tearing apart our lives.
「じゃあアタシがナイフ放た前のその口を、この口で塞いであげましょう」
"Then I'll plug that mouth before you throw your knife with this mouth of mine."
相対のチュー
A reciprocal kiss.
キミは今からアタシの息を吸って生きている
From now on, you're living by breathing my breath.
言葉はもう唾液で錆び付いていた
Our words had already rusted with saliva.
ねえいつかの僕らはまた笑えるのかな
Hey, will we ever be able to smile again someday?
ねえ君は今さら僕の息を吸って
Hey, now you're breathing my breath after all this time...
「大好き」なんて言ってみるの
trying to say "I love you".
ねえ僕も好きだよ
Hey, I love you too.
「どうして」なんていらない
"Why?" isn't necessary.
離さないから
Because I won't let go.
何度も君と生きよう
Let's live together over and over.
僕らはもういっそボンボンのように一生二人吐く言葉吸って息絶えて
We might as well burn out like pom-poms, breathing each other's words for a lifetime.
空回りしそう でもまだ止めないで
We're spinning our wheels, but don't stop us yet.
空回りしそう 声を聞かせてよ
We're spinning our wheels, let me hear your voice.
あんたはここまで 後ろだけ見とけ あんたはここまで
You're only going this far. Just watch your back.
抱き占めたいから 2本足で歩く
I want to hold you close, so I walk on two legs.
一人じゃ寂しいから君と息すうよ
I'm lonely on my own, so I'll breathe with you.
抱き占めたいから 2本足で歩く
I want to hold you close, so I walk on two legs.
一人じゃ寂しいから君と息すうよ
I'm lonely on my own, so I'll breathe with you.
余裕で生き切って 全部BETだぜ イエイ☆
Live it up with ease, bet it all, yeah!
そこもだけ そこも愛 括るの アタシら
That place too, that love too—we define them.
Stay もういい 勝ったなら 平常心
Stay. Whatever, if you win, stay calm.
ねぇプレイボーイ 行って Don't get in my way じゃれてないで
Hey playboy, go on. Don't get in my way, stop messing around.
ワンツー スリー ワンツー スリー ワンツー スリー
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three
めったかなバイバイ ナイツリー
A careless bye-bye on a night tree.
ワンツー スリー ワンツー スリー ワンツー スリー
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three
特報！
[Breaking News!]
フルアニメーションMV
[Full Animation MV]
配信後プレミア公開！
[Premiere after the stream!]
MV公開に先駆けてー
[Ahead of the MV release—]
ARE YOU READY?
痛くて目を塞いでも
Even if it hurts and I close my eyes,
聞こえちゃう不安ショウ
I still hear that anxiety show.
悩んでも変わらないから
Worries won't change anything,
なんだかんだやるしかないか
so sooner or later, I've just got to do it.
壊れるならいっそ直しやすいように
If it's going to break, I hope it's easy to fix—
どんな形目指せるかな
what shape can I aim for?
助走なしのジャンプ 紐なしでダイブ
A jump without a run-up, a dive with no tether.
今日のあたし 褒めてあげたいじゃんか
Don't you want to praise me for today?
息したい もっと響きたい ねえあたし以上が見れるかも
I want to breathe, I want to resonate more. Hey, I might see beyond myself.
妄想止まんないや
My delusions won't stop.
ファッションビート
Fashion Beat
喰い込んでみたい夢に愛想尽かされて 吐きやしないな
Trying to bite into dreams, losing patience with love, I won't give up.
叶えるのはあたし自身か それとも誰かにお任せか
Will I fulfill it myself, or leave it to someone else?
ただただ自分に勝ちたいの
I just, just want to win against myself.
ニューファッションビート 愛を喰らうな
New Fashion Beat, don't devour love.
負けるなんてごめんだ味がないな
Losing is out of the question, it's tasteless.
何度も灰になる進化 生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Evolution of turning to ash over and over, personification of rebirth bugs.
まだまだ腐ってあげないそう、ないな
I won't let myself rot away yet, no, never.
チクチク刺してくるのは 飽き飽きしてるわ
I'm sick and tired of those constant pricks.
ごめん鬱陶しい言葉遊びは どうかちゃんと仕舞っておいて
Sorry, please properly put away those annoying word games.
私こそがライバル 当たり前の解釈 どうしたらいい わかってるのに
I am my own rival, a matter-of-course interpretation. Even though I know what to do,
助走なしのジャンプ 紐なしでダイブ
A jump without a run-up, a dive with no tether.
今日のあたし 出来る気しないだって
Thinking I have no chance of doing it today—
気にしないなんて無理じゃない？ ねえあたし以外と比べても
isn't it impossible not to care? Hey, even if I compare myself to others,
クソつまんないじゃんか
it's totally boring.
ファッションビート 喰い込んでみちゃう？
Fashion Beat, want to try biting into it?
夢にありそうなんて吐きやしないな
I'm not gonna say it's like a dream
叶えるのはあたし自身か
Is it myself who makes it happen,
それとも誰にお任せか
or do I leave it to someone else?
ただただ自分に勝ちたい
I just, just want to win against myself
ニュー ファッションビート
New Fashion Beat,
愛を喰らう
devouring love
負けるなんてごめんだ 味がないな
Losing is out of the question, it's tasteless
何度も灰になる進化 生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Evolution turning to ashes, personification of rebirth bugs
まだまだ腐ってあげない そう、ない
I'm still not gonna rot away, yeah, no
止まれない
I can't stop
誰かじゃないあたし自身か 生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Not someone else, but myself, personification of rebirth bugs
まだまだ散ってあげない そう、ない
I'm still not gonna scatter away, yeah, no
みんなライブ来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you everyone for coming to the live!
これからは告知の時間です。まずは、こちら！
Now it's announcement time. First, this one!
さくらみこ 誕生日記念2026 記念グッズです！
Sakura Miko Birthday Anniversary 2026 commemorative goods!
まずは1つ目、こちら、ジャン！
First is the first item, ta-da!
アクリルパネル！
Acrylic panel!
イラストレーターはおるだん先生に描き下ろしていただきました！
The illustration was drawn specially by Ordan-sensei!
テーマは「天野巫女界の巫女」！
The theme is 'Miko of the Amano Miko World'!
新衣装の巫女を描き下ろしてもらいました！
They drew the new costume Miko for us!
オーロラ加工でキラキラのアクリルパネルとなっております！めっちゃ可愛い！
It's a sparkly acrylic panel with aurora finishing! Super cute!
続いては、こちら！
Next is this!
スマホスタンドフィギュアです！
Smartphone stand figure!
スマホが立てかけられるスタンド、そして新衣装の巫女のフィギュア！
A stand to hold your smartphone, plus a figure of Miko in her new outfit!
めちゃくちゃ可愛くないですか？これたくさんこだわったのでね、ぜひね、あの、このスタンドにスマホを立てかけて配信観てくれたら嬉しいです！
Isn't it super cute? I put a lot of work into it, so I'd be super happy if you put your phone on this stand and watch the stream!
続いては、こちら！ガジェットケース！
Next is this! Gadget case!
新衣装にちなんで、ちょっとこういうね、あんまり出さないグッズも考えてみました！ケーブルとかね、モバイルバッテリーなど、小物も収納できるケースとなっております！
Inspired by the new outfit, I thought of goods like this that aren't usually released! It's a case that can store small items like cables and mobile batteries!
ソフトな素材になっているよ！
It's made of soft material!
最後は、こちら！ナイロンジャケット！
Last is this! Nylon jacket!
新衣装をモチーフにしたナイロンジャケットとなっております！ちょっとかっこいいめのデザインなので、みんな一緒にお揃いになってくれたら嬉しいです！
It's a nylon jacket themed after the new outfit! It has a slightly cool design, so I'd be happy if everyone wears matching ones!
そしてフルセット購入特典は、こちら！
And the full set purchase bonus is this!
さくらみこ直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードとなっております！
It's a postcard with Sakura Miko's handwritten signature and hot-stamped duplicate message!
まぁちょっと数量限定にはなるんですが、みんなお早めによろしくお願いします！
Well, it'll be in limited quantity, but please check it out early everyone!
そして通常版は、さくらみこ箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りのポストカードとなっております！
And the regular version is a postcard with Sakura Miko's hot-stamped duplicate signature and message!
みんな、あの、ぜひたくさん手に入れてくれると嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！
Everyone, um, I'd be happy if you could get lots of them! Thank you!
そして、告知2つ目は、こちら！
And the second announcement is this!
なんと！さくらみこ×Gakkenさんの参考書シリーズ発売決定になりました！
What! Sakura Miko x Gakken reference book series release has been decided!
ホロライブ Study Book さくらみこでもわかるシリーズとなっております！
It's the Hololive Study Book 'Even Sakura Miko Can Understand' series!
中学漢字＋語彙、中学数学、中学英単語、中学地理＋都道府県の4冊が発売決定です！
Four books are decided for release: Junior High Kanji + Vocabulary, Junior High Math, Junior High English Vocabulary, and Junior High Geography + Prefectures!
そして、初回限定の愛蔵版も発売予定となっております！
And a first-edition limited collector's edition is also scheduled for release!
4月下旬頃より予約開始なので、引き続き続報チェックしてね！みこでもわかるシリーズ、うーん、みんな説得力があると思うよね！
Reservations start around late April, so keep checking for further updates! The 'Even Sakura Miko Can Understand' series... well, everyone thinks it's persuasive, right?
次！3つ目は、こちら！
Next! The third one is this!
さくらみこ×フレーベル館 初の絵本！みこぴーとおおきなさくらのきが本日より発売です！
Sakura Miko x Froebel-Kan's first picture book! 'Miko-pi and the Big Sakura Tree' goes on sale starting today!
もう買ってくれた人もいるかな？
I wonder if some people have already bought it?
いつも支えてくれているみこぴーを題材に、夢だった絵本を作ることができました！
Using Miko-pi, who always supports me, as the theme, I was able to make a picture book which was my dream!
全国の書店やローソンさんで購入可能なので、ぜひぜひみんな手にとってください！よろしくお願いします！頑張りました！
It's available for purchase at bookstores and Lawson stores nationwide, so please everyone pick it up! Thank you! I worked hard!
続いてはこちら、大発表！4つ目は、こちら！
Next is this, a big announcement! The fourth one is this!
さくらみこフィギュア化が決定しました！
Sakura Miko's figure adaptation has been decided!
おるだん先生監修にて、みこの夢だった等身大フィギュアがついに完成です！やったー！
Under Ordan-sensei's supervision, Miko's dream life-size figure is finally complete! Yay!
スケールフィギュアも同時に予約販売が決まりました！
Pre-order sales for the scale figure have also been decided at the same time!
明日3月6日から予約開始です！EXPOのデザインココさんブースで展示されるので、みんな見に来てね！たくさん写真撮ってね！
Pre-orders start tomorrow, March 6th! It will be exhibited at Design COCO's booth at EXPO, so everyone come see it! Take lots of pictures!
また、この等身大フィギュアも展示される京都IP書店×さくらみこのおしゃれショップも開催決定となりました！すごい！
Also, a POP UP SHOP collaboration between Kyoto IP Bookstore and Sakura Miko where this life-size figure will be exhibited has also been decided! Amazing!
リニューアルオープンした京都ツタヤIP書店
The newly reopened Kyoto Tsutaya IP Bookstore
京都IP書店オープン記念 POP UP SHOP 開催決定！
Kyoto IP Shoten Pop-Up Shop grand opening announced!
2026年4月28日から
Starting from April 28, 2026!
オリジナルグッズの発売やノベルティのコラボも行われるので
Featuring original goods releases and novelty collaborations,
皆さん、楽しみにしていてください！
so everyone, please look forward to it!
盛りだくさんだー！
It's packed with goodies!
そして、まだまだございます！
And there's still more!
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
さくらみこ×HYTEコラボPCケース発売決定！
Sakura Miko x HYTE collaboration PC case release decided!
キーキャップとデスクマットのセットでございます！
It's a set featuring keycaps and a desk mat!
成功やリリースなどのメール通知や詳細についてはHYTE.co/miwakaを見てみてください！
For email notifications on sales and releases, and more details, check out HYTE.co/miwaka!
楽しみにしといてね！
Be sure to look forward to it!
そして、今年もさくらみこ×鳴門鯛焼き本舗さんのコラボが実施中です！
And this year, the Sakura Miko x Naruto Taiyaki Honpo collaboration is underway!
今年でなんと2回目です！ありがとうございます！
Incredible, it's already our second year! Thank you so much!
3月31日までなのでみんなぜひ食べに行ってください！
It runs until March 31st, so everyone please go try it!
続いて、
Next up,
新曲「ファッションビート」本日0時よりリリースです！
my new song 'Fashion Beat' is releasing today at midnight!
MVはこのあとプレミア公開！みんな見てね！
The MV premieres right after this! Everyone check it out!
とっても豪華なアニメMVとなっております！よろしくお願いします！
It's a super lavish anime MV! Please check it out!
はい！そしてこちら、明日からホロライブエキスポのセカンドフェス開催です！
And right here, starting tomorrow is the Hololive Expo 7th fes!
3日間の開催です！すごい！
It's a 3-day event! Amazing!
みこはですね、セカンドフェスではDay2のステージ2に参加します！みんな見に来てね！
As for me, I'll be performing on Day 2 Stage 2! Everyone come watch!
このあとはメンバー限定の撮影会もあるのでみんなみこぴーになってね！
Afterwards there's also a member-only photo session, so everyone become a 35P!
ということで、告知がもりもりだくさんのもりになりましたが、みんなついてきてくれたかな？
So, we've got an absolute mountain of announcements, did everyone keep up?
みここからも頑張るのでよろしくお願いします！
Miko will keep doing her best too, so thank you for your support!
誕生日祝ってくれてありがとう！おつみこー！
Thank you for celebrating my birthday! Otsumiko!
生誕LIVE2026♡ 今年も祝ってくれてありがとうじぇ〜♡ みんなのおかげでたくさんのことを乗り越えてみごとしてるよ。まだまだ笑っていこう!! そしてこれからも歩み続ける初心の心で「アイドルがんばる!!」さくらみこ 2026.3.5
[Birthday LIVE 2026] Thank you so much for celebrating with me again this year! Thanks to everyone, I've been able to overcome so many things, and seeing you all smile makes me want to laugh even more!! And with the same fresh heart as when I first started, I'll keep pushing forward as an idol!! Sakura Miko 2026.3.5